Cool, so we've got our little character here
in the forest, hopping along and the grid
outdoors, so happy to
be outside, wild and free.
Now, what we're going to do is we're going
to add some obstacles to make this a little
bit more game-like, so we're going to go
into our assets folder, go to our obstacles,
go, oh, kind of like
this barrier, kind of
looks like a fence, so
we'll go and drop this
into our hierarchy, and we're just going to
position this a little farther back, let's
call it, let's put it like the edge of the
screen, like right there, cool, perfect.
So now that we have
our barrier, you can see
that it has nothing for
components, so we're
going to have to add
some things like a box
collider, so that the
player can collide with
it, cool, and we'll
just resize this box
collider really quick,
so we've set up our box
collider so that it
looks really nice, cool,
that's perfect, now
we're actually going to
add a rigid body, so
now this is an actual
physical object in the
scene that the player
can actually run into and collide with, and
it'll use physics, so it might topple over
if you run into it, if
you notice, we actually
didn't check the is
trigger box on the box
collider, that's because
this isn't actually a
collider that will have
us destroy the object
or anything, it's just so that we know when
we run into it, and then we're just going
to rename this barrier, this fence really
quick, and we're going to call it obstacle,
now what we're going
to do is in our assets
folder, we're going to
make a prefab, because
we're going to use this
again, so we're going
to make a prefab's folder, and then we'll
take our obstacle, and we'll left click,
drag it down into
prefabs, so now we'll make
an original prefab, and
here you can see that
we have this fence saved, and now that we
have this prefab saved, we're actually going
to make it move in the
scene, so we're going
to make a script, and we'll call it move
left, very simple name, because it'll just
make things move left,
so now we'll take the
move left script,
apply it to our obstacle,
and then just make
sure that we override our
obstacle to apply it
to all of our prefabs,
and then in our move
left script, we're just
going to open it up really quick, now inside
of our move left script, we're going to
create a variable for
speed, so this will just
be private, and it'll
be a float, because we
can always just edit
it inside of our code
later, we'll call it speed, and we'll set
it to 30 for now, and then we're actually
going to move this
using our transform.
translate once again instead
of trying to use physics
to move a fence, so
we'll just transform
translate, like we always
do, and then we're going
to move it to the left, since the fence
is to the right of the player, so vector 3.
left, we want this to move
over time instead of moving
every single frame,
so we'll use time.
delta time, and then we'll
move it at the speed that
we set, and then if we save, so now in unity
when we press play, our fence flies at a
really fast speed at
the player, and I think
we're just flying off
into the distance, there
it goes, so we can
always change the speed
of that to something
less later, what we can
do for now is because
we're actually making
look like the player is
running, we're actually
just going to move everything around the
player to make it look like they're running,
so if we actually take
this move left script,
then we apply it to our background, this
now creates the illusion when we press play,
that our player is
running through the scene,
even though in fact
the player's not moving
at all, you're going to make the player look
like they're moving, so what you're going
to do is grab an obstacle
from the obstacles
folder, create it, make
sure that you add a
box collider, a rigid body, if you want you
can even add the move left script now, then
add it to your scripts
folder, and then you can
create your prefabs
folder, drag the obstacle
down into prefabs, and then your move left
script, you're going to give it a speed, so
just set it for 30 for now, in your update
method you're just going to move it through
translating the transform,
so we're going to
move it to the left,
over time add a certain
speed, and then a
nice little effect that you
can do is on your
background, you can actually
add the move left
script, so then that way
when you press play,
it looks like the player
is moving to the
right, when in fact
everything else is moving
to the left, now it's your turn.